{"queries": [{"answer": "D", "choices": ["a priori. ", "objective. ", "empirical. ", "subjective. "], "question": "If an analyst estimates the probability of an event for which there is no historical record, this probability is best  described as:    \t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["Z-spread minus the option cost. ", "Z-spread plus the cost of the option. ", "value of the security's embedded option. ", "effect of changes in interest rates on the value of the security. "], "question": "The option adjusted spread (OAS) is best described as the:    \t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["ratio. ", "ordinal. ", "interval. ", "nominal. "], "question": "An analyst gathered the price-earnings ratios (P/E) for the firms in the SP 500 and then ranked the firms from highest to  lowest P/E. She then assigned the number 1 to the group with the lowest P/E ratios, the number 2 to the group with the  second lowest P/E ratios, and so on. The measurement scale used by the analyst is best described as:    \t"}, {"answer": "D", "choices": ["an externality. ", "project sequencing. ", "a mutually exclusive project. ", "an example of investment synergy. "], "question": "Howard Quarries has recently opened a limestone quarry at a location outside their traditional service area. Because  limestone is a major ingredient in concrete, if the quarry is successful Howard plans to build a ready-mix concrete plant at  the same location. The investment in the concrete plant is best described as:    \t"}, {"answer": "D", "choices": ["marginal cost of capital. ", "cost of new debt capital. ", "cost of retained earnings. ", "weighted average cost of capital. "], "question": "A company's optimal capital budget is best described as the amount of new capital required to undertake all projects with an  internal rate of return greater than the:    \t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["ordinal.", "interval.", "nominal."], "question": "An analyst gathers the price-earnings ratios (P/E) for the firms in the S&P 500 and then ranks the firms from highest to lowest P/E. She then assigns the number 1 to the group with the lowest P/E ratios, the number 2 to the group with the second lowest P/E ratios, and so on. The measurement scale used by the analyst is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["marginal cost of capital.", "cost of new debt capital.", "weighted average cost of capital."], "question": "A company\u2019s optimal capital budget is best described as the amount of new capital required to undertake all projects with an internal rate of return greater than the:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["only interest payments to debt holders.", "payments to both debt holders (interest and principal) and preferred stockholders.", "both interest and principal payments to debt holders, but not payments to preferred stockholders."], "question": "Free cash flow to equity is most accurately described as operating free cash flow adjusted for:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["a priori.", "empirical.", "subjective."], "question": "If an analyst estimates the probability of an event for which there is no historical record, this probability is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["an externality.", "project sequencing.", "an example of investment synergy."], "question": "A company recently opened a limestone quarry at a location outside its traditional service area. Because limestone is a major ingredient in concrete, if the quarry is successful the company plans to build a ready-mix concrete plant at the same location. The investment in the concrete plant is best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["escalation bias.", "confirmation bias.", "overconfidence bias."], "question": "The behavior of investors who put more money into a failure that they feel responsible for, rather than into a success, is most accurately described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["interest rate cap.", "interest rate floor.", "interest rate collar."], "question": "A series of interest rate put options that expire on different dates but have the same exercise rate is best defined as a (n):\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["Z-spread minus the option cost.", "Z-spread plus the cost of the option.", "value of the security\u2019s embedded option."], "question": "The option adjusted spread (OAS) is best described as the:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["geometric mean return.", "time-weighted rate of return.", "money-weighted rate of return."], "question": "On 7 January 2008, an investor purchases 100 shares of stock for $32.50 a share. On 7 January 2009, the investor purchases 100 more shares of the same stock for $36.70 a share. On 7 January 2010, the investor sells all 200 shares of the stock for $42.00 a share. The internal rate of return for this investment is best described as an example of a:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["elastic.", "inelastic.", "unit elastic."], "question": "If a price cut of a product increases total revenue, demand is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["elastic.", "inelastic.", "perfectly elastic."], "question": "A company determines that the quantity demanded of a product increases by 5% when price is reduced by 10%. The product\u2019s price elasticity of demand is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["equal.", "lower.", "higher."], "question": "The quantity theory of money is best described as the proposition that, in the long run, an increase in the quantity of money brings a percentage increase in the price level that is:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["objective of financial reporting.", "general requirement for financial statements.", "qualitative characteristic of the IFRS Framework."], "question": "Under International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) the preparation of a complete set of financial statements is best described as a(n):\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["the amount of proceeds received in exchange for the obligation.", "the discounted value of the future cash flows that are required to satisfy the obligation.", "the undiscounted amount of cash or cash equivalents expected to be paid to satisfy the obligation."], "question": "The settlement value for a liability is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["growth stock.", "cyclical stock.", "speculative stock."], "question": "A company has furnished the following information: Return on equity 20% Earnings retention rate 50% Current dividend per share (Do) paid on the company\u2019s common stock \u20ac2.00 Required rate of return on the company\u2019s common stock 15% Current stock price \u20ac50 Company\u2019s P/E ratio 30x Industry average P/E ratio 20x Stock\u2019s beta 0.7 According to the dividend discount model and the other data given, the company\u2019s stock is best described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["overvalued by $11.36.", "undervalued by $15.13.", "undervalued by $36.36."], "question": "A company\u2019s $100 par perpetual preferred stock has a dividend rate of 7 percent and a required rate of return of 11 percent. The company\u2019s earnings are expected to grow at a constant rate of 3 percent per year. If the market price per share for the preferred stock is $75, the preferred stock is most appropriately described as being:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["loan to the futures trader.", "requirement set by federal regulators.", "down payment from the futures trader."], "question": "Margin in the futures market is most accurately described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["a return based on the return of another asset.", "an adjustment to another asset\u2019s level of risk.", "an agreement between two parties to provide something for each other."], "question": "A derivative is most accurately defined as a financial instrument that provides:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["risk per unit of mean return.", "mean return per unit of risk.", "mean excess return per unit of risk."], "question": "For an investment portfolio, the coefficient of variation of the returns on the portfolio is best described as measuring:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["leptokurtic.", "mesokurtic.", "platykurtic. By accessing this mock exam, you agree to the following terms of use: This mock exam is provided to currently-registered CFA candidates. Candidates may view and print the exam for personal exam preparation only. The following activities are strictly prohibited and may result in disciplinary and/or legal action: accessing or permitting access by anyone other than currently-registered CFA candidates; copying, posting to any website, emailing, distributing and/or reprinting the mock exam for any purpose."], "question": "If a probability distribution is very similar to a normal distribution, then the kurtosis is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["equal for the two projects.", "lower for Project 1 than for Project 2.", "greater for Project 1 than for Project 2."], "question": "An analyst is developing net present value (NPV) profiles for two investment projects. The only difference between the two projects is that Project 1 is expected to receive larger cash flows early in the life of the project, while Project 2 is expected to receive larger cash flows late in the life of the project. The sensitivities of the projects\u2019 NPVs to changes in the discount rate is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["call market.", "dealer market.", "primary market."], "question": "A security market in which all the bids and asks for a stock are gathered to arrive at a single price that satisfies most of the orders is best described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["range notes.", "structured notes.", "medium-term notes."], "question": "Corporate debt securities that are offered continuously to investors by an agent of the issuer are best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["if the population distribution is normal.", "if the population distribution is symmetric.", "for populations described by any probability distribution."], "question": "The Central Limit Theorem is best described as stating that the sampling distribution of the sample mean will be approximately normal for large-size samples:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["sample standard deviation.", "standard error of the sample statistic.", "appropriate value from the t-distribution ."], "question": "A test statistic is best defined as the difference between the sample statistic and the value of the population parameter under H0 divided by the:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["substitutes.", "complements.", "inferior goods."], "question": "If the quantity demanded of pears falls by 4% when the price of apples decreases by 3%, then apples and pears are best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["best efforts.", "bought deal.", "competitive bidding."], "question": "An investment banking firm offers a corporation a binding bid to purchase an amount of new debt securities to be issued by the corporation with a specified coupon rate and maturity. The corporation can accept or reject this bid. This type of security distribution is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["H0: 9 = 90 versus Ha: 9 ^ 90", "H0: 9 < 90 versus Ha: 9 > 90", "H0: 9 > 90 versus Ha: 9 < 90"], "question": "When an investigator wants to test whether a particular parameter is larger than a specific value, the null and alternative hypothesis are best defined as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["Type I error.", "Type II error.", "test with little power."], "question": "A hypothesis test fails to reject a false null hypothesis. This is best described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["elastic.", "inelastic.", "perfectly elastic."], "question": "Over a given period, the price of a commodity falls by 5.0% and the quantity demanded rises by 7.5%. The price elasticity of demand for the commodity is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["fixed in the long run.", "variable in the long run.", "variable in the short run."], "question": "Regarding a company\u2019s production function, both labor costs and capital costs are best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["cost-push inflation.", "demand-pull inflation.", "monetarist cycle theory."], "question": "Suppose inflation increases due to increases in government spending and a reduction in taxes. Such inflation is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["operational.", "allocational.", "informational."], "question": "The type of efficiency that exists in an economy that uses resources in such a way that they are most valuable is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["step-up note.", "floating-rate bond.", "deferred coupon bond."], "question": "A 10-year bond is issued on January 1, 2010. Its contract requires that its coupon rate change over time as shown in the following table: Coupon Payment Date Range Coupon Rate 01/01/2010-12/31/2011 2.0% 01/01/2012-12/31/2013 5.0% 01/01/2014-12/31/2015 7.5% 01/01/2016-12/31/2019 9.0% This security is best described as an example of a:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["default risk.", "downgrade risk.", "credit spread risk."], "question": "An investor fears that economic conditions will worsen and the market prices of her portfolio of investment-grade corporate bonds will decrease more than her portfolio of government bonds. The investor\u2019s fear is best described as a fear of:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["Default risk.", "Liquidity risk.", "Prepayment risk."], "question": "The primary motivation for creating a collateralized mortgage obligation (CMO) is best described as the desire to redistribute which risk of investment in residential mortgages?\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["P(A).", "P(B).", "P(B|A)."], "question": "If two events, A and B, are independent and the probability of A does not equal the probability of B (i.e., P(A) * P(B)), then the probability of event A given that event B has occurred (i.e., P(A | B)) is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["support.", "resistance.", "change in polarity."], "question": "A low price range in which buying activity is sufficient to stop a price decline is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["a triple bottom.", "a head and shoulders.", "an inverse head and shoulders."], "question": "A technical analyst has detected a price chart pattern with three segments. The left segment shows a decline followed by a reversal to the starting price level. The middle segment shows a more pronounced decline than in the first segment and again a reversal to near the starting price level. The third segment is roughly a mirror image of the first segment. This chart pattern is most accurately described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["always less than or equal to zero.", "always greater than or equal to zero.", "at times positive and at other times negative."], "question": "Consumer surplus is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["Qb and Qa.", "Qc and Qb.", "Qc and Qa."], "question": "The diagram illustrates a consumer's allocation of her budget between items X and Y. With an initial budget (BC1) she consumes Qa units of item Y. When the price of Y drops, she consumes Qc units of item Y. Lines BC2 and BC3 are parallel to one another. The income effect arising from this change in the price of Y is best described as the distance between:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["an oligopoly.", "perfect competition.", "monopolistic competition."], "question": "If the minimum efficient scale of a single producer is small relative to the demand for an undifferentiated good, the market structure of the producer is best described as being:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["equal weighting.", "fundamental weighting.", "float-adjusted market-capitalization weighting."], "question": "The index weighting that results in portfolio weights shifting away from securities that have increased in relative value (e.g., decrease in book-to-market) toward securities that have fallen in relative value whenever the portfolio is rebalanced is most accurately described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["Mode", "Mean", "Median"], "question": "For a positively skewed unimodal distribution, which of the following measures is most accurately described as the largest?\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["sample.", "statistic.", "conditional distribution."], "question": "A subset of a population is best described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["lepto-kurtosis.", "positive skewness.", "negative skewness. By accessing this mock exam, you agree to the following terms of use: This mock exam is provided to currently registered CFA candidates. Candidates may view and print the exam for personal exam preparation only. The following activities are strictly prohibited and may result in disciplinary and/or legal action: accessing or permitting access by anyone other than currently registered CFA candidates and copying, posting to any website, e-mailing, distributing, and/or reprinting the mock exam for any purpose."], "question": "A graphic depiction of a continuous distribution that shows the left tail to be longer than the right tail is best described as having:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["increases.", "decreases.", "is eliminated."], "question": "First degree price discrimination is best described as pricing that allows producers to increase their economic profit while consumer surplus:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["verifiability.", "comparability.", "understandability."], "question": "Under the IASB Conceptual Framework, one of the qualitative characteristics of useful financial information is that different knowledgeable users would agree that the information is a faithful representation of the economic events that it is intended to represent. This characteristic is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["financial reporting.", "the auditor's report.", "financial statement analysis."], "question": "Providing information about the performance of a company, its financial position, and changes in financial position that is useful to a wide range of users is most accurately described as the role of:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["statutory voting.", "voting by proxy.", "cumulative voting."], "question": "The type of voting in board elections that is most beneficial to shareholders with a small number of shares is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["arbitrage transaction.", "balance sheet transaction.", "capital infusion transaction."], "question": "When a bank creates a collateralized loan obligation (CLO) to divest of commercial loans that it owns, the process is best described as a(n):\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["market risk.", "systematic risk.", "unsystematic risk."], "question": "Risk that can be attributed to factor(s) that impact a company or industry is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["basing pattern consisting of five smaller waves.", "Fibonacci ratio percentage retracement composed of three smaller waves.", "uptrend moving above the high of Wave 1 and consisting of five smaller waves."], "question": "In Elliott Wave Theory, Wave 2 commonly exhibits a pattern best described as a(n):\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["adverse opinion.", "qualified opinion.", "disclaimer of opinion."], "question": "In the audit report, an additional paragraph that explains an exception to an accounting standard is best described as a(n):\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["trial balance.", "general ledger.", "general journal."], "question": "An accounting document that records transactions in the order in which they occur is best described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["sales risk.", "business risk.", "operating risk."], "question": "A firm is uncertain about both the number of units the market will demand and the price it will receive for them. This type of risk is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["size of the contract.", "original time to maturity.", "net amount owed by one party to the other."], "question": "The tenor of a swap is best described as the:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["market factor model.", "fundamental factor model.", "macroeconomic factor model."], "question": "A return-generating model that provides an estimate of the expected return of a security based on factors such as earnings growth and cash flow generation is best described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["platykurtotic (less peaked than a normal distribution).", "leptokurtotic (more peaked than a normal distribution).", "mesokurtotic (identical to the normal distribution in peakedness)."], "question": "Equity return series are best described as, for the most part:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["support level.", "resistance level.", "change in polarity point."], "question": "A stock is declining in price and reaches a price range wherein buying activity is sufficient to stop the decline. This is best described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["risk of loss relative to an investment's fair value if the investment needs to be converted to cash quickly.", "increased sensitivity of the market value of debt to a change in market interest rates as maturity is extended.", "possibility that the borrower will fail to make a promised payment at the contracted time and in the contracted amount."], "question": "The liquidity premium can be best described as compensation to investors for the:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["as liquid.", "less liquid.", "more liquid."], "question": "The current ratio for an industry is 3.2. Data for a firm in the industry is presented below: As at December 31 \u00a3 '000s Cash 200 Accounts receivable 350 Inventory 1,250 Accounts payable 300 Taxes payable 200 Installment loan payable, due in three equal annual payments on June 30. 600 Using the current ratio, when compared with the industry, the firm is best described as being:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["timeliness and accrual accounting.", "understandability and verifiability.", "relevance and faithful representation."], "question": "According to the International Accounting Standards Board's Conceptual Framework for Financial Reporting, the two fundamental qualitative characteristics that make financial information useful are best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["swap.", "futures contract.", "forward contract."], "question": "A corporation issues 5-year fixed-rate bonds. Its treasurer expects interest rates to decline for all maturities for at least the next year. She enters into a 1-year agreement with a bank to receive quarterly fixed-rate payments and to make payments based on floating rates benchmarked on 3- month LIBOR. This agreement is best described as a:\t"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["price return.", "collateral yield.", "convenience yield."], "question": "If an investor uses derivatives to make a long investment in commodities, the return earned on margin is best described as:\t"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["failing to reject a false null hypothesis.", "rejecting a true alternative hypothesis.", "rejecting a true null hypothesis."], "question": "A Type I error is best described as the probability of:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["Ha: 60% versus Ha: 6< 0%.", "Ho: 0< 0, versus H;: 0 > 00.", "H\u00f3: 0 = 0, versus H,: 0 # 00."], "question": "When an investigator wants to test whether a particular parameter is greater than a specific value, the null and alternative hypothesis are best defined as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["perfectly elastic.", "inelastic.", "elastic."], "question": "Over a given period, the price of a commodity falls by 5.0%, and the quantity demanded rises by 7.5%. The price elasticity of demand for the commodity is best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["always greater than or equal to zero.", "at times positive and at other times negative.", "always less than or equal to zero."], "question": "Consumer surplus is best described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["general ledger.", "general journal.", "trial balance."], "question": "An accounting document that records transactions in the order in which they occur is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["Transparency to the underlying economics", "Consistency in the measurement basis used across the balance sheet", "Uniform treatment of transactions by different entities"], "question": "Which of the following is best described as a necessary characteristic for an effective financial reporting framework?"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["timeliness and accrual accounting.", "relevance and faithful representation.", "understandability and verifiability."], "question": "According to the International Accounting Standards Board's (IASB) Conceptual Framework for Financial Reporting, the two fundamental qualitative characteristics that make financial information useful are best described as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["the audit report.", "financial statement analysis.", "financial reporting."], "question": "Providing information about the performance of a company, its financial position, and changes in financial position that is useful to a wide range of users is most accurately described as the role of:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["less than the investment opportunity schedule.", "equal to the investment opportunity schedule.", "greater than the investment opportunity schedule."], "question": "The optimal capital budget for a firm is best described as occurring when the company's marginal cost of capital is:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["fundamental weighting.", "float-adjusted market-capitalization weighting.", "equal weighting."], "question": "The index weighting that results in portfolio weights shifting away from securities that have increased in relative value toward securities that have fallen in relative value whenever the portfolio is rebalanced is most accurately described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["mental accounting.", "the disposition effect.", "the gambler's fallacy."], "question": "The behavioral bias in which investors tend to avoid realizing losses but rather seek to realize gains is best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["fundamental factor model.", "macroeconomic factor model.", "market factor model."], "question": "A return-generating model that provides an estimate of the expected return of a security based on such factors as earnings growth and cash flow generation is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["Mean", "Median", "Mode"], "question": "For a positively skewed unimodal distribution, which of the following measures is most accurately described as the largest?"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["test with little power.", "Type I error.", "Type II error."], "question": "A hypothesis test fails to reject a false null hypothesis. This result is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["change in polarity.", "support.", "resistance."], "question": "A price range in which selling is sufficient to stop the rise in price is best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["opportunity cost.", "required return.", "sunk cost."], "question": "Once an investor chooses a particular course of action, the value forgone from alternative actions is best described as a(n):"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["increases.", "is eliminated.", "decreases."], "question": "First-degree price discrimination is best described as pricing that allows producers to increase their economic profit while consumer surplus:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["oligopoly.", "perfect competition.", "monopolistic competition."], "question": "The market structure in which a firm sells all of the product it produces at the market equilibrium price is best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["publicly advocating for global accounting standards and convergence.", "mandating that non-US issuers provide a reconciliation to US GAAP.", "requiring issuers to provide disclosures describing key differences."], "question": "The SEC's approach to addressing the significant differences in financial reporting under International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) and US GAAP is best described as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["higher.", "equivalent.", "lower."], "question": "Data for a firm are presented in the following table: As of 31 December \u00a3 thousands Cash 200 Accounts receivable 350 Inventory 1,250 Accounts payable 300 Taxes payable 200 Installment loan payable, due in three equal annual payments on 30 June. 600 The current ratio for the firm's industry is 3.2. Based on the current ratio, the firm's liquidity compared with the industry is best described as being:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["business risk.", "operating risk.", "sales risk."], "question": "A firm is uncertain about both the number of units the market will demand and the price it will receive for them. This type of risk is best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["cumulative voting.", "statutory voting.", "voting by proxy."], "question": "The type of voting in board elections that is most beneficial to shareholders with a small number of shares is best described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["forward contract.", "swap.", "futures contract."], "question": "A corporation issues five-year fixed-rate bonds. Its treasurer expects interest rates to decline for all maturities for at least the next year. She enters into a one-year agreement with a bank to receive quarterly fixed-rate payments and to make payments based on floating rates benchmarked on three-month LIBOR. This agreement is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["high ability and willingness.", "high ability and low willingness.", "low ability and high willingness."], "question": "You are preparing an investment policy statement for a client who manages her own successful marketing consultancy. Her annual income is approximately $500,000. She describes herself as a finance novice. Most of her savings are invested in bank term deposits and short-term government securities. In her responses to the standard risk assessment questionnaire, she strongly agrees with the statements that she \"feels more comfortable putting money in a bank account than in the stock market.\" Also, she \"thinks of the word 'risk' as being a 'loss\". Based on this information, your client's ability and willingness to take risk can best be described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["mesokurtotic.", "leptokurtotic.", "platykurtotic."], "question": "Equity return distributions are best described as being:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["Mode", "Median", "Mean"], "question": "For a positively skewed unimodal distribution, which of the following measures is most accurately described as the largest?"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["subjective probability.", "a priori probability.", "empirical probability."], "question": "A fund manager would like to estimate the probability of a daily loss higher than 5% on the fund he manages. He decides to use a method that uses the relative frequency of occurrence based on historical data. The resulting probability is best described as a(n):"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["minimum amount of loss expected over a given time period at a given probability level.", "time period during which a fixed amount is lost at a given probability level.", "probability of losing a fixed amount of money over a given time period."], "question": "The value at risk of an alternative investment is best described as the:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["futures contract.", "forward contract.", "swap."], "question": "A corporation issues five-year fixed-rate bonds. Its treasurer expects interest rates to decline for all maturities for at least the next year. She enters into a one-year agreement with a bank to receive quarterly fixed-rate payments and to make payments based on floating rates benchmarked on three month LIBOR. This agreement is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["amount needed to finance the purchase of the underlying asset.", "minimum account balance required as prices change.", "performance bond ensuring fulfillment of the obligation."], "question": "When purchasing a futures contract, the initial margin requirement is best described as the:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["float-adjusted market-capitalization weighting.", "equal weighting.", "fundamental weighting."], "question": "The index weighting that results in portfolio weights shifting away from securities that have increased in relative value toward securities that have fallen in relative value whenever the portfolio is rebalanced is most accurately described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["comparability.", "verifiability.", "understandability."], "question": "Under the International Accounting Standards Board's (IASB's) Conceptual Framework, one of the qualitative characteristics of useful financial information is that different knowledgeable users would agree that the information is a faithful representation of the economic events that it is intended to represent. This characteristic is best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["H%: 0 < 0, versus Ha: Q > 00.", "H%: 02 0, versus H: 0 < 00.", "H%: 0 = 0, versus Ha: 0 # 0,."], "question": "When an investigator wants to test whether a particular parameter is greater than a specific value, the null and alternative hypothesis are best defined as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["change in polarity point.", "support level.", "resistance level."], "question": "A stock is declining in price and reaches a price range wherein buying activity is sufficient to stop the decline. This range is best described as the:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["required return.", "sunk cost.", "opportunity cost."], "question": "Once an investor chooses a particular course of action, the value forgone from alternative actions is best described as a(n):"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["Median", "Mean", "Mode"], "question": "For a positively skewed unimodal distribution, which of the following measures is most accurately described as the largest?"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["A candlestick chart", "A bar chart", "A point and figure chart"], "question": "The following chart is best described as an example of which type of technical analysis chart? 180 175 170 165 Price ($) E g a a 150 145 140 135 13) TTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTIN 1 4 7 10 13 16 19 22 25 28 31 34 37 40 43 46 49 52 Week"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["change in polarity point.", "resistance level.", "support level."], "question": "A stock is declining in price and reaches a price range wherein buying activity is sufficient to stop the decline. This range is best described as the:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["a Student's t.", "lognormal.", "normal."], "question": "If a stock's continuously compounded return is normally distributed, then the distribution of the future stock price is best described as being:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["total population of people who are of working age.", "labor force.", "labor force minus frictionally unemployed."], "question": "The unemployment rate is best described as the ratio of unemployed to:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["increases.", "decreases.", "is eliminated."], "question": "First-degree price discrimination is best described as pricing that allows producers to increase their economic profit while consumer surplus:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["a restrictive form of scenario analysis.", "providing a distribution of possible solutions to complex functions.", "an approach to backtest data."], "question": "Monte Carlo simulation is best described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["internal rate of return.", "required rate of return.", "expected return."], "question": "The minimum rate of return an investor must receive in order to accept an investment is best described as the:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["parameter.", "frequency distribution.", "sample statistic."], "question": "A descriptive measure of a population characteristic is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["Qp and Qa.", "Qe and Qa.", "Q. and Q."], "question": "The diagram to the below illustrates a consumer's allocation of her budget between items X and Y. With an initial budget (BC1) she consumes Qa units of item Y. When the price of Y drops, she consumes Qunits of item Y. Lines BC2 and BC3 are parallel to one another. Quantity of X nuypa /.. -- -- - --BC3 BC2 Qa QQ6 Quantity of Y The income effect arising from this change in the price of Y is best described as the distance between:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["inferior goods.", "complements.", "substitutes."], "question": "If the quantity demanded of pears falls by 4% when the price of apples decreases by 3%, then apples and pears are best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["acceptable despite the risk of manipulation by management.", "a factor that reduces the understandability of financial statements.", "avoidable through sophisticated accounting and auditing techniques."], "question": "The use of estimates in financial reporting is best described as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["float-adjusted market-capitalization weighting.", "equal weighting.", "fundamental weighting."], "question": "The index weighting that results in portfolio weights shifting away from securities that have increased in relative value toward securities that have fallen in relative value whenever the portfolio is rebalanced is most accurately described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["the gambler's fallacy.", "the disposition effect.", "mental accounting."], "question": "The behavioral bias in which investors tend to avoid realizing losses but rather seek to realize gains is best described as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["forward contract.", "option contract.", "asset."], "question": "Convenience yield is best described as a nonmonetary benefit of holding a(n):"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["market factor model.", "macroeconomic factor model.", "fundamental factor model."], "question": "A return-generating model that provides an estimate of the expected return of a security based on such factors as earnings growth and cash flow generation is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["opportunity cost.", "sunk cost.", "required return."], "question": "Once an investor chooses a particular course of action, the value forgone from alternative actions is best described as a(n):"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["if the population distribution is symmetrical.", "for populations described by any probability distribution.", "if the population distribution is normal."], "question": "The central limit theorem is best described as stating that the sampling distribution of the sample mean will be approximately normal for large-size samples:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["normal.", "lognormal.", "a Student's t."], "question": "If a stock's continuously compounded return is normally distributed, then the distribution of the future stock price is best described as being:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["test with little power.", "Type Il error.", "Type I error."], "question": "A hypothesis test fails to reject a false null hypothesis. This result is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["decreases.", "is eliminated.", "increases."], "question": "First-degree price discrimination is best described as pricing that allows producers to increase their economic profit while consumer surplus:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["complements.", "substitutes.", "preferences."], "question": "In the demand function f = 4.3 \u2013 0.7P +.031 \u2013 .05Pwhere Q\u00cb represents the quantity demanded of a good X, Px is the price per unit of good X, I is consumers' income, and Py is the price per unit of good Y, X, and Yare best described as:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["facilitating resource allocation decisions by current and potential investors and creditors.", "reporting an entity's economic resources and claims, and changes therein, to shareholders.", "providing information about financial performance to a wide range of users."], "question": "The objective of general purpose financial reporting is best described as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["promoting the use of International Financial Reporting Standards and the convergence of national accounting standards.", "enforcing financial reporting requirements for entities participating in capital markets.", "promoting cross-border cooperation and uniformity in securities regulation."], "question": "The role of the International Organization of Securities Commissions (IOSCO) is best described as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["mandating that non-US issuers provide a reconciliation to US GAAP.", "requiring issuers to provide disclosures describing key differences.", "publicly advocating for global accounting standards and convergence."], "question": "The SEC's approach to addressing the significant differences in financial reporting under International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) and US GAAP is best described as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["the overreaction effect.", "data mining.", "momentum."], "question": "A trader is able to obtain persistent abnormal returns by adopting an investment strategy that purchases stocks that have recently experienced high returns. This strategy exploits a market pricing anomaly best described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["the systematic risk of a security, using the index as a proxy for the entire market.", "the difference between the return of the actively managed portfolio and the return of the passive portfolio.", "a measure of market sentiment."], "question": "Security market indices can be used to calculate alphas, which are best described as:"}, {"answer": "C", "choices": ["strong.", "weak.", "semi-strong."], "question": "If a test rejects the hypothesis that market prices reflect private information but does not reject the hypothesis that they reflect past market data and public information, then the form of market efficiency is best described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["futures contract.", "swap.", "forward contract."], "question": "A corporation issues five-year fixed-rate bonds. Its treasurer expects interest rates to decline for all maturities for at least the next year. She enters into a one-year agreement with a bank to receive quarterly fixed-rate payments and to make payments based on floating rates benchmarked on three-month LIBOR. This agreement is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["high ability and low willingness.", "high ability and willingness.", "low ability and high willingness."], "question": "You are preparing an investment policy statement for a client who manages her own successful marketing consultancy. Her annual income is approximately $500,000. She describes herself as a finance novice. Most of her savings are invested in bank term deposits and short-term government securities. In her responses to the standard risk assessment questionnaire, she strongly agrees with the statements that she \"feels more comfortable putting money in a bank account than in the stock market.\" Also, she \"thinks of the word 'risk' as being a 'loss\". Based on this information, your client's ability and willingness to take risk can best be described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["probability of rejecting a true null hypothesis.", "probability of correctly rejecting the null hypothesis.", "same as the level of significance of the test."], "question": "When testing a hypothesis, the power of a test is best described as the:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["parameter.", "frequency distribution.", "sample statistic."], "question": "A descriptive measure of a population characteristic is best described as a:"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["substitutes.", "inferior goods.", "complements."], "question": "If the quantity demanded of pears falls by 4% when the price of apples decreases by 3%, then apples and pears are best described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["Consistency in the measurement basis used across the balance sheet", "Transparency to the underlying economics", "Uniform treatment of transactions by different entities"], "question": "Which of the following is best described as a necessary characteristic for an effective financial reporting framework?"}, {"answer": "A", "choices": ["relevance and faithful representation.", "understandability and verifiability.", "timeliness and accrual accounting."], "question": "According to the International Accounting Standards Board's (IASB) Conceptual Framework for Financial Reporting, the two fundamental qualitative characteristics that make financial information useful are best described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["equal weighting.", "fundamental weighting.", "float-adjusted market-capitalization weighting."], "question": "The index weighting that results in portfolio weights shifting away from securities that have increased in relative value toward securities that have fallen in relative value whenever the portfolio is rebalanced is most accurately described as:"}, {"answer": "B", "choices": ["the gambler's fallacy.", "the disposition effect.", "mental accounting."], "question": "The behavioral bias in which investors tend to avoid realizing losses but rather seek to realize gains is best described as:"}]}